l aura **Marsh**

Front End Software Engineer Los Angeles, CA

marshlau97@gmail.com | 510 456 8670 | lauralynnmarsh.com | git:/lauramarsh | in:/laura-marsh-lm

Summary_

Current Software Engineer at an Al SaaS startup with 2+ years total experience specializing in frontend development and design. Computer/art nerd who loves React & color theory, and enjoys modularizing ui components for reusability. Interested in working in an engineering-motivated environment and improving my working relationship with all parts of the web and mobile stack.

Skills

- · HTML, CSS, Javascript ES6, SQL, Python
- · React, Redux, Styled Components, Sass, Bootstrap, Node
- · VSCode, Git, Adobe Photoshop

Work Experience_

Beyond Limits AI Glendale, CA

Front End Engineer

May 2019 - PRESENT

- · Led the frontend/UX redesign of a fast-paced project with a significant UI rework.
- \cdot Developed high-performing front ends for various projects, delivered several past POC & MVP phases.
- Used Javascript ES6, React, Feathers JS, Redux, Node to build large-scale single page applications.
 Interacted with MongoDB and PostgreSQL databases. Versioned using Bitbucket + Git.
- · Worked with data scientists and industry representatives during requirements gathering/analysis and implemented AI and data visualization solutions using Plotly.js.

Capital Group, American Funds

Irvine, CA

Software Engineering Capstone Intern

Apr 2018 - Sep 2018

- · Delivered a micro app with client-side features simulating the creation of a financial investment portfolio.
- Used vanilla JS and Google Maps, Alpha Vantage APIs to build tools that gathered user input for analysis, created and displayed a mock portfolio & located nearby office locations/financial advisors geographically.
- Defined application structure and routers using python & flask. Engaged in initial requirements phases to develop ux and site flow. Designed graphic visuals to help educate and maintain user interest.

TenantBase Irvine, CA

Front End Engineering Intern

Jun 2017 - Sep 2017

- · Achieved 10% increase in visitor traffic and retention on the main product by improving SEO and enhancing page speed optimization.
- · Collaborated with market researchers to generate appropriate location-based search data.
- Updated legacy Django site using Wagtail for database management and GeoJSON for dynamically generating available real estate listings within input geographic search parameters
- Implemented feature flags to toggle different page templates for user feedback/testing.

Dell EMC Menlo Park, CA

Firmware OA Intern

Jun 2015 - Sep 2015

- \cdot Vetted cloud servers for DSSD, a startup revolutionizing cloud storage technologies and procedures.
- · Created test suites in Python to verify basic product firmware/hardware operations. Updated existing suites to match product requirements.

Projects_

Moving Palettes

HTML/CSS, JS, React, Feathers JS, MongoDB

· A single-page React app that generates a gif or cinemagraph alongside a corresponding randomized color palette. Designed for ease, aesthetics, and efficiency between database and UI.

FabFlix

HTML/CSS, JS, AJAX, JQuery, Java, SQL, Apache TomCat, AWS EC2

- · A movie browsing full-stack eCommerce web application populated with XML data gathered from IMDB.
- · UI includes fuzzy/full-text search, built following MVC architecture alongside a mirroring Android app.
- · Used MySQL DBs with stored procedures/external functions for data management alongside load balancing on master/slave db instances.

Education

B.S. in Software Engineering, University of California, Irvine